<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Environment on RCT</title>
    <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/tags/environment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Environment on RCT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 20:08:37 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/tags/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Environmental Development Activities</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 20:08:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d/</guid>
      <description>Environmental programmes are one among the prime activities of the Real Charitable Trust. It has been concentrating more on these aspects jointly with government and non-government agencies. The main aim of this program is to create a garbage-free and hygienic society. The prime concept of this objective is to Refuse, Reduce, Reuse and Recycle the unwanted garbage. The following activities are going on through this important venture,
  Collection and segregation of garbage, distribution of bins to encourage the public in SWM Disposal of unwanted garbage Initiating income generation programs for the rag pickers and other weaker section of the people Creating awareness among the people especially educational institutions about pollution, environment, and hygiene Health and Hygienic awareness programme Educating people to refuse plastic bags and products Practising of the aerobic method of composting Production of vermin manure Initiating tree plantation and urban gardening Awareness of Health and Hygiene and Toilet clean campaign in Government and Corporation Schools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apollo Tyres Foundation- Clean My Transport Nagar (2015-2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:08:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d-copy/</guid>
      <description>The Clean My Transport Nagar (CMTN) targets to improve waste management and cleanliness of certain transport Nagar (hubs) in India. The initiative also aims to generate awareness on health and sanitation among stakeholders. Real Charitable Trust was privileged to work alliance with Apollo Tyres Foundations, in CMDN Truck Terminal, Madhavaram, Chennai, Tamil Nadu. We are being in these activities since from 2015, and implementing the mission of Apollo Tyres Foundation “Clean My Transport Nagar”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRISIL Foundation - 360o Approach Equip and Empower the Rag Pickers Through SWM.</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d-copy-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:08:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d-copy-7/</guid>
      <description>CRISIL Foundation, as it stands today, is a public charitable trust. Set up in March 2013, we are CRISIL’s corporate social responsibility (CSR) arm, reaching out to socially and economically disadvantaged communities within and beyond our areas of operations. CRISIL Foundation’s flagship financial capability-building programme empowers disadvantaged communities by strengthening their financial capabilities.
Real Charitable Trust is much privileged to be connected with CRISIL’s corporate social responsibility (CSR) arm. We had been with the alliance of CRISIL by the concept of 360-degree Approach, to equip and empower the rag pickers through the solid waste management system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Oil Corporation-School Intervention Programme (2015-2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d-copy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:08:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d-copy-2/</guid>
      <description>Indian Oil is country’s largest commercial enterprise and flagship national Oil Company Apart from providing petroleum products which are crucial to turning the wheels of progress of the nation, Indian Oil also understands the importance of creating a benevolent social impact of its work and minimizing the adverse impact of energy use on ecology. Indian Oil’s Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) is guided by its corporate vision of caring for the environment and community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual Household Latrine Construction (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d-copy-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:08:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d-copy-3/</guid>
      <description>Under Swachh Bharat Mission, Ministry of Housing and Urban Affairs announced the IHHL Scheme (Individual Household Latrine Construction). The vision of this project is to have toilets for every individual household and keep surrounding as open defecation free. The Target Group for construction of household units of Toilets, thus, is: (i) 80% of urban households engaging in open defecation (ii) All households with unsanitary latrines (iii) All households with single-pit latrines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industrials and Institutions (2017-2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d-copy-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:08:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d-copy-6/</guid>
      <description>We have been working in solid waste management programme since from 2007 in an urban-rural area, exactly in Chennai, Kancheepuram and Thiruvallur Districts. We are also carrying out Gardening and solid waste management in different parts of the above areas. Especially we are handling waste management and maintenance at T.V.K Industrial Estate, SIDCO, Guindy, of Chennai District and Tirumazhisai Industrial Estate, SIDCO, Tirumazhisai of Thiruvallur District, and Mambakkam Sipcot, Asian Paints, Metecno of Kancheepuram District for past five years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ONGC- Health and Hygiene Programme (2015-2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d-copy-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:08:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d-copy-4/</guid>
      <description>As a public sector enterprise, Oil and Natural Gas Corporation Limited (ONGC) has a long and cherished tradition of commendable initiatives, institutionalized programs and practices of Corporate Social Responsibility which have played a laudable role in the development of several underdeveloped regions of the country. ONGC ensures that its corporate social responsibility (CSR) engagements are impactful and deliver sustainable change in the lives of our stakeholder communities, including Employees, Shareholders, Vendors, and Operational Communities Real Charitable Trust is much privileged to be connected with ONGC corporate social responsibility (CSR) activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resource Recovery Center Maintenance (2018- )</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d-copy-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:08:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d-copy-5/</guid>
      <description>We are also being given the order to carry on the Resource recovery centres of Greater Chennai Corporation Zone-3, Madhavaram. Monitoring and maintenance of the resource recovery centre, where all the segregated waste would come from different divisions of zone 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>