<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Women on RCT</title>
    <link>https://realcharitabletrust.org/tags/women/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Women on RCT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:06:36 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://realcharitabletrust.org/tags/women/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Empowerment activities</title>
      <link>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/women/c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:06:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/women/c/</guid>
      <description> Women are the potential resource for any development in the society. They play a pivotal role in shaping the family, which is the basic unit of the larger community. Our trust realizes the key function and catalyst role of the woman in the society and has organized rural and urban women in the following developmental programs,
  Formation of women association Motivation and awareness creation Promotion of savings and credit societies Self Help Schemes Training programs on Income generation, production and marketing Health awareness programs and medical camps Legal, social-political awareness &amp;mdash;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formation of Self Help Group (SHG) (2016-2018)</title>
      <link>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/women/c-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:05:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/women/c-copy/</guid>
      <description>The self-help group movement, largely confined to women until now, is being extended to men in the area. Real Trust, has established around 80 women SHGs and 5 men at various locations in the year 2016. Members of the groups have a regular meeting and are motivated. Our main goal is ensuring holistic development of women and girls under distress through counselling and Rehabilitation measures. We also provide membership training, animators and representative training and EDP training for income generation activities at Nehru Nagar, MGR Nagar, C.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>