<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Youth on RCT</title>
    <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/tags/youth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Youth on RCT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 18:42:04 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/tags/youth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Youth Development Activities</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/youth/b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 18:42:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/youth/b/</guid>
      <description> Youth force is one of the significant of the society and tapping the potentials of the youth force is crucial for the integrated development of the community. The trust does it all in a simple way and shows the youth ways and means to grow well through the following program:
  Organizing and motivating youth especially unorganized and slum youth groups Creating awareness on socio-economic, political, education, cultural, moral and health aspects Awareness on HIV/AIDS ,TB &amp;amp; Anti-Tobacco programs Conducting vocational skills Health and Hygienic Training on Income generation programs Rehabilitation Career guidance and job placement Individual and Group counselling Media awareness  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzhal Central jail Intervention-Community College (2017-2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/youth/b-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 18:41:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/youth/b-copy/</guid>
      <description>As the Community Colleges were emerging there was the need felt by the Colleges to have a coordinating agency, Indian Centre for Research and Development of Community Education (ICRDCE) one among them to help and serve the Community College Movement. Alliance with ICRDCE, Real Charitable Trust, strived in implementing this project for the convicted prisoners for their development of skills and improves their education for their livelihood through Mahatma Gandhi Community college.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>