<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on RCT</title>
    <link>https://realcharitabletrust.org/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on RCT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 20:16:36 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://realcharitabletrust.org/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Health and Aged Care Programme</title>
      <link>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/health/e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 20:16:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/health/e/</guid>
      <description>The main aim of this program is to create awareness among people, especially those most disadvantaged in society, about the welfare measures. Real Charitable Trust has been concentrating more awareness programs to highlight the State and Central government schemes in all developmental sectors.
 Programs, such as awareness camps, seminars, rallies, etc., are conducted regularly with the help of government agencies and like-minded NGOs. These programs encourage people to utilize government organizations’ facilities in the promotion of their own personal development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Care for the Aging</title>
      <link>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/health/e-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:16:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/health/e-copy/</guid>
      <description>Aged people are the most uncared for and isolated members of society. Many of the families feel that aged parents are a burden to the growth of the family. It is difficult for poor families to support their aged members and often these people are left without care.
Based on the objectives of the trust, the following activities have been carried out successfully for the past 10 years:
 Creating security by placing them in their own homes Extending counselling to create self-confidence Carrying out health programs Extending recreation programs to refresh their mind and body Distributing basic amenities Reunion with the families Accommodating helpless in the ageing home  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NULM-Shelter for Urban Homeless-Men (2016-2018)</title>
      <link>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/health/e-copy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:16:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/health/e-copy-2/</guid>
      <description>National Urban Livelihoods Mission (NULM) aims at providing permanent shelter equipped with essential services to the urban homeless in a phased manner under the Scheme of Shelter for Urban Homeless (SUH).
The objectives of the Shelter for Urban Homeless (SUH) component of NULM scheme are to:
 Ensure availability and access of the urban homeless population to permanent shelters including the basic infrastructure facilities like water supply, sanitation, safety and security.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>