<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pagenav on RCT</title>
    <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/tags/pagenav/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pagenav on RCT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 18:40:47 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/tags/pagenav/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Children Development Activities</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/children/a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 18:40:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/children/a/</guid>
      <description>It is important to have a strong foundation in every aspect of the personality such as emotional, social, mental and physical of children. We aim was to develop positive school cultures on the basis of the rights of the child and to improve achievement for all children through having schools and early childhood education centres become learning communities that know, promote, and live human rights and responsibilities. At present, our trust reaches out around 1200 children in the slums of north Chennai as well as rural areas through the following programs,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youth Development Activities</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/youth/b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 16:39:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/youth/b/</guid>
      <description> Youth force is one of the significant of the society and tapping the potentials of the youth force is crucial for the integrated development of the community. The trust does it all in a simple way and shows the youth ways and means to grow well through the following program:
  Organizing and motivating youth especially unorganized and slum youth groups Creating awareness on socio-economic, political, education, cultural, moral and health aspects Awareness on HIV/AIDS ,TB &amp;amp; Anti-Tobacco programs Conducting vocational skills Health and Hygienic Training on Income generation programs Rehabilitation Career guidance and job placement Individual and Group counselling Media awareness  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Empowerment activities</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/women/c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 14:35:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/women/c/</guid>
      <description> Women are the potential resource for any development in the society. They play a pivotal role in shaping the family, which is the basic unit of the larger community. Our trust realizes the key function and catalyst role of the woman in the society and has organized rural and urban women in the following developmental programs,
  Formation of women association Motivation and awareness creation Promotion of savings and credit societies Self Help Schemes Training programs on Income generation, production and marketing Health awareness programs and medical camps Legal, social-political awareness  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environmental Development Activities</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 13:30:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/environmental/d/</guid>
      <description>Environmental programmes are one among the prime activities of the Real Charitable Trust. It has been concentrating more on these aspects jointly with government and non-government agencies. The main aim of this program is to create a garbage-free and hygienic society. The prime concept of this objective is to Refuse, Reduce, Reuse and Recycle the unwanted garbage. The following activities are going on through this important venture,
  Collection and segregation of garbage, distribution of bins to encourage the public in SWM Disposal of unwanted garbage Initiating income generation programs for the rag pickers and other weaker section of the people Creating awareness among the people especially educational institutions about pollution, environment, and hygiene Health and Hygienic awareness programme Educating people to refuse plastic bags and products Practising of the aerobic method of composting Production of vermin manure Initiating tree plantation and urban gardening Awareness of Health and Hygiene and Toilet clean campaign in Government and Corporation Schools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health and Aged Care Programme</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/health/e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 12:25:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/projects/health/e/</guid>
      <description>The main aim of this program is to create awareness among people, especially those most disadvantaged in society, about the welfare measures. Real Charitable Trust has been concentrating more awareness programs to highlight the State and Central government schemes in all developmental sectors.
 Programs, such as awareness camps, seminars, rallies, etc., are conducted regularly with the help of government agencies and like-minded NGOs. These programs encourage people to utilize government organizations’ facilities in the promotion of their own personal development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>