<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Children on RCT</title>
    <link>https://realcharitabletrust.org/tags/children/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Children on RCT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 18:32:47 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://realcharitabletrust.org/tags/children/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Children Development Activities</title>
      <link>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/children/a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 18:32:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/children/a/</guid>
      <description>It is important to have a strong foundation in every aspect of the personality such as emotional, social, mental and physical of children. We aim was to develop positive school cultures on the basis of the rights of the child and to improve achievement for all children through having schools and early childhood education centres become learning communities that know, promote, and live human rights and responsibilities. At present, our trust reaches out around 1200 children in the slums of north Chennai as well as rural areas through the following programs,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Children Sangam (2016-2018)</title>
      <link>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/children/a-copy-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 18:32:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/children/a-copy-3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;Real Charitable Trust actively formed 200 Children’s Sangam in and around Chennai, Thiruvallur and Kanchipuram district of Tamil Nadu. Advocated through Children Sangam meetings on Child Rights, promotion of quality Anganwadi centers with Pacca building, Construction of child-friendly toilet, Protected drinking water, Electricity facilities, Display of information board about the services of Anganwadi centers (indoor and outdoor services), Playground and compound wall facilities, Smoke free kitchen, Kitchen garden and Observation of Anganwadi Day on November 21st.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skill Development Training Program (NCLP)-(2017-2018)</title>
      <link>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/children/a-copy-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 18:32:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/children/a-copy-4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;The government had initiated the National Child Labour Project (NCLP) Scheme in 1988 to rehabilitate working children in 12 child labour endemic districts of the country. The project societies are required to conduct a survey to identify children working in hazardous occupations and processes. These children will then form the target group for the project society. Of the children identified those in the age group 5-8 years will have to be mainstreamed directly to the formal education system through the SSA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplementary Education Centre - (2015-2018)</title>
      <link>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/children/a-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 18:32:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/children/a-copy/</guid>
      <description>&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;Real Charitable Trust implemented conducting supplementary education centre at Nehru Nagar, Megzinepuram, C Kalyanapuram Sundaram Street, RR Nagar, Singaravelar Nagar of North Chennai and Kothimangalam village, Malaninatham village, Irumbuli village of Kanchipuram District to provide special coaching for 10th and Higher secondary students including Spoken English, Summer camps for Slum and Rural Children. This programme was funded by LMK Enterprises and as of now actively we reached around 800 children through this programme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walk and Talk Program- The Eureka SPARK Programme (2016-2018)</title>
      <link>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/children/a-copy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 18:32:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://realcharitabletrust.org/projects/children/a-copy-2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;Real Charitable Trust implemented to organize supplementary centres to provide easy way teaching English for Slum and Urban children totally with 5 centres at North Chennai for urban and for rural children 5 centres at Kanchipuram district. Totally around 450 children were supported through this programme. It was a programme of AID India for street and working children. This program followed the method to Training of Teacher initially who will educate the students, next mobilize the right candidate and provide and distribute the kit for training, and finally train and certify the beneficiaries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>