<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>projects on Real Charitable Trust</title>
    <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in projects on Real Charitable Trust</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 16:39:04 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Youth Development Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/youth-development-projects/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 16:39:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/youth-development-projects/home/</guid>
      <description>Tapping the potentials of youth force is very crucial for the holistic development of the Nation. RCT works with the youth of the Nation who are in need of quality education, skills development, health, personality development, etc. The trust educates the youth for taking up major social and entrepreneurial roles in the society through carrier guidance and leadership training programs.
Our trust is dedicated to imparting moral values, ethics, skills, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Empowerment Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/women-empowerment-projects/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 14:35:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/women-empowerment-projects/home/</guid>
      <description>Women empowerment projects encourage them to improve their livelihood. We have formed Self Help Groups (SHG) for women to be independent. Empowering women is everyone’s basic duty and we appeal to everyone who is reading this to take care of the women in your family and give your love, time, energy and financial freedom for them. When women in your family live happily, the society grows and so does a Nation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environmental protection Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/environmental-protection-projects/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 13:30:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/environmental-protection-projects/home/</guid>
      <description>RCT aims to create a clean and green environment. The projects are hygiene improvement, afforestation, Solid Waste Management, Say NO to plastics, building proper Sanitation facilities, etc. We work with government and NGOs create a litter-free and hygienic environment. The objective is to Reduce, Reuse and Recycle.
The following activities are a part of environmental protection  Solid Waste Management. Clearing garbage from houses and the environment. Creating awareness about environmental protection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elderly Care Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/elderly-care-projects/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 12:25:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.realcharitabletrust.org/elderly-care-projects/home/</guid>
      <description>We feel that today’s generation has better compassion and respect for the elders than their previous generation which witnessed a lot of financial and family hurdles forcing them to leave elders at old age homes or alone. If you take social media and cinema, youngsters share a lot of useful thoughts and messages about caring elders. We at RCT has given old age homes, not just for accommodation and food, but also to enable to join with their families again, provide employment, healthcare and complete rehabilitation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>